I'm Mario Ritter with the VOA Special English Education Report. Some American
parents might think their children need better educations to compete with China
and other countries. But how much do the parents themselves need to change? A new
book called Battle Him of the Tiger Mother by Amy Chua has caused a debate about
cultural differences in parenting. Ms. Chua is a professor at the Yale Law School in
New Haven, Connecticut and the mother of two daughters. She was raised in the
American Midwest by immigrant Chinese parents. In the Chinese culture, the Tiger
represents strength and power. In her book, Ms. Chua writes about how she demanded
excellence from her daughters. For example, she threatened to burn her daughter's
stuffed animals unless she played a piece of music perfectly. She would insult her
daughters if they failed to meet her expectations. Ms. Chua says she had a clear
list of what her daughters, Sophia and Luisa, were not permitted to do. They could
not attend a sleepover. Have a play date. Watch TV or play computer games. Be in a
school play or get any grade less than an A. Many people have criticized Amy Chua.
Some say her parenting methods were abusive. She even admits that her husband,
who is not Chinese, sometimes objected to her parenting style. But she says that
was the way her parents raised her and her three sisters. Ms. Chua makes fun of
her own extreme style of parenting. She says she eased some of the pressure after her
younger daughter rebelled and shouted, I hate my life, I hate you. Ms. Chua says
she decided to retreat when it seemed like there was a risk that she might lose
her daughter. But she also says American parents often have low expectations of their children's
abilities. She says one of the biggest differences I see between Western and Chinese parents
is that Chinese parents assume strength rather than fragility. Stacey DeBroff has written
four books on parenting. She says the debate over Ms. Chua's book has to do with two questions.
What does it mean to be a successful parent? And what does it mean to be a successful child?
Ms. DeBroff says Amy Chua's parenting style is not limited to Chinese families. She says it
represents a traditional way of parenting among immigrants seeking a better future for their children.
But she also sees a risk. When children have no time to be social or to follow their own interests,
they might not develop other skills that they need to succeed in life. Stacey DeBroff advises
parents to develop their own style of parenting and not just repeat the way they were raised.
And that's the VOA Special English Education Report. What are your thoughts about parenting styles
and cultural differences? Tell us at VOAspecialEnglish.com or on Facebook at VOA Learning English.
For VOA Special English, I'm Mario Ritter.